



Marcelo Dias Schneider

Nationality: Italian, Brazilian

(+39) 3497966478

Date of birth: 14/01/1992

Gender: Male

■ Email address: marcelo.d.schneider@gmail.com

Website: http://marceloschneider.dev.br/

in LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/marcelo-dias-schneider-6392ba94/

• Address: Via Fonteiana, 126 Interno 2, 00152 Roma (Italy)

ABOUT ME

I am a fullstack web programmer, between 2012 and 2016 I had experiences in developing a management system for a travel agency, in ganeiro 2021 I went back to work as a fullstack web programmer and currently work with data management for e-commerce sites (CMS as WooCommerce, Prestashop and Shopify) through their api.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Web developers

Sellmasters SRL [14/01/2021 - Current]

City: Rome Country: Italy

I currently work as a Developer Fullstack, with the opportunity to put my knowledge of Javascript and PHP programming languages into practice, using frameworks such as Laravel 8, VueJS 3 (Vue Router 4 and Vuex 4). I am responsible for managing the products and orders of our suppliers in the (CMS) E-commerce sales channels.

- Interactions with e-commerce via REST API with JSON or XML:
- Publication of our supplier's products on sales channels such as Shopify, WooCommerce and Prestashop.
- Update of prices and available quantities of products published in the sales channels.
- · Read and write files on FTP servers with management of large amounts of data.
- Merge catalog of products from different warehouses getting available quantity of products based on SKU or EAN.
- Management of scripts to be runned daily with CronJob.
- Retrieve and manipulate data from sales channels to generate reports.
- Development of a application to manager the company:
- Backend in php (Laravel 8)
- Frontend in Javascript (VueJS 3) + HTML e CSS (Bootstrap 5):
- Communication between backend and frontend with REST API.
- User access controls with JWT token.

Socio Fundatore

Plinc Viagens e Turismo LTDA [01/05/2012 - 31/10/2016]

City: Gramado Country: Brazil

This was my first experience as an entrepreneur, being responsible for the administration of the company together with another partner, in the first year we hired a Fullstack developer and together with him we developed the internal management system of the agency for the control of hotel reservations, tours and airline tickets, with the generation of payment reports for customers and suppliers.

This was my first contact with HTML, CSS, PHP and MySQL languages, with this experience I have always been looking for more knowledge in programming in my spare time. After leaving the company, I continued to study Web Development.

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

Algorithm - Programing Logic

Curso em Video | CEV Treimanetos informatica e Serviços [01/01/2018 - 30/06/2018]

Address: Rua Massenet 421, Rio de Janeiro (Brazil)

https://www.cursoemvideo.com/cursos/

HTML 5 CSS 3

Curso em Video | CEV Treimanetos informatica e Serviços [01/07/2018 - 30/10/2018]

Address: Rua Massenet 421, Rio de Janeiro (Brazil)

https://www.cursoemvideo.com/cursos/

Basic PHP

Curso em Video | CEV Treimanetos informatica e Serviços [01/07/2018 - 30/11/2018]

Address: Rua Massenet 421, Rio de Janeiro (Brazil)

https://www.cursoemvideo.com/cursos/

PHP OOP

Curso em Video | CEV Treimanetos informatica e Serviços [01/01/2019 - 30/06/2019]

Address: Rua Massenet 421, Rio de Janeiro (Brazil)

https://www.cursoemvideo.com/cursos/

MySQL

Curso em Video | CEV Treimanetos informatica e Serviços [01/01/2019 - 30/06/2019]

Address: Rua Massenet 421, Rio de Janeiro (Brazil)

https://www.cursoemvideo.com/cursos/

Javascript

Curso HTML 5 e CSS 3 New Features [01/07/2019 - 30/11/2019]

Address: Rua Massenet 421, Rio de Janeiro (Brazil)

https://www.cursoemvideo.com/cursos/

Computer network

Curso em Video | CEV Treimanetos informatica e Serviços [01/07/2019 - 30/11/2019]

Address: Rua Massenet 421, Rio de Janeiro (Brazil)

https://www.cursoemvideo.com/cursos/

Git and GitHub

Curso em Video | CEV Treimanetos informatica e Serviços [01/07/2020 - 30/10/2020]

Address: Rua Massenet 421, Rio de Janeiro (Brazil)

https://www.cursoemvideo.com/cursos/

Curso HTML 5 e CSS 3 New Features

Curso em Video | CEV Treimanetos informatica e Serviços [01/06/2021 - 30/06/2021]

Address: Rua Massenet 421, Rio de Janeiro (Brazil)

https://www.cursoemvideo.com/cursos/

LANGUAGE SKILLS

Mother tongue(s): Portuguese

Other language(s):

English Italian

LISTENING B2 READING B2 WRITING B1 LISTENING B2 READING B2 WRITING B2

SPOKEN PRODUCTION B1 SPOKEN INTERACTION B1 SPOKEN PRODUCTION B2 SPOKEN INTERACTION B2